So when interviewing Johan two years
ago for the podcast, we spoke about
making 100, 000 in one year and it
was impressive, but since then he's
been really killing it, hacking not
only on GitLab, but also programs
like Apple, Google, or Yahoo.
And in this interview, I'll
try to uncover all his secrets.
So enjoy my interview with Johan Carlsson.
Hello, Johan.
How are you doing?
How has these two years been to you?
Oh, thanks for having me again.
Yeah, you're
the first, the first guest
that makes a second appearance.
Yeah, no, I'm, uh, I'm
having a great time.
It's been, uh, so has it been two years?
Yes.
The previous episode was in
January, 2023 for the record.
We were recording this in December, 2024
and you also in, in person in Sweden.
Uh, so, um, it's almost two years.
Yeah.
That's a crazy in a lot, in many ways.
And yeah, it's been, uh, It's been a ride,
uh, and, uh, a lot of things are the same,
uh, and, uh, some things have changed.
I'm still, uh, on GitLab, uh, and, uh,
uh, but I also hunt on other programs and,
uh, but I think the, the big thing, of
course, is that I've gone, uh, full time.
Yes.
That's a big thing.
Uh, from what I did previously.
Um, so I'm from this from August, so
it's almost, I guess it's like four
months or something, but I also did
three months, uh, before the summer
where I just tried it out, like taking
a break from my regular job and, uh,
testing it to see if it could fly.
What pushed you to quit your job?
It was a combination of, I really, it
was not a problem with the job per se.
I was working as a developer,
like front end developer.
I was a combination of the being
able to be more free with my time.
Uh, having a big family and being able
to like do whatever I want with my
time, uh, and also with my interest in,
uh, like security and that I, I didn't
really get to like fulfill that, uh,
doing, uh, regular development work.
Yeah.
So.
How has the, the life
changed since you quit?
What did you expect it to be?
Uh, yeah, I mean, I guess so.
Uh, I've had a lot of, it
has changed in many ways.
It's not related to bug boundaries.
Like I got my fourth, uh,
child, uh, during this time.
Uh, so it's, I mean, I've, I've
been doing it full time, but I
have not been working full time.
I've been a full time hunter, but
my time has been, uh, a bit, uh,
scattered between the different things,
but it has given me like the feeling
of like, I can control what I do
myself, which has been, uh, amazing.
And when we spoke two years ago.
I felt like I'm saying the same things,
but then it seemed incredible that you
climbed the GitLab leaderboard so quickly.
I don't remember which place
you were at two years ago.
No, I
don't remember.
I was top 10 at least.
Top
10 something.
And I was like, wow, he made
top 10 in GitLab in one year.
But, uh, it seems like the bugs have to
stop somewhere yet, you know, not, not
two years have passed and you're now
top one, huge congratulations on that.
And how on earth is it
possible there's still so
many bugs?
I mean, that was definitely one of my
big milestones, uh, that I wanted to
reach because when I got at the top 10.
That I think you could get into top 10.
I don't remember the numbers now, but
you can be at least like around one K in
reputation points or something like that.
And the people at the top at
that time had like three K.
So it still felt like
there's a long way to go.
Yeah, exactly.
And, uh, I think I almost
made one K reputation points,
uh, this year or something.
It's like, so in the end I've, I did,
uh, uh, a huge, uh, uh, rush, uh, but
I mean, so that's also the strange
thing with this reputation scoreboards
that they keep this, a lot of the
people at the top 10 are not really
active hunters on GitLab anymore.
Yeah.
So.
Uh, I think I'm definitely one of,
um, they've added this new feature
on HackerOne where you can actually
see scoreboards for each year
instead, so you can pick a year
and they will like rearrange it.
And uh, I've been number one all
of these years, except one for some
reason, some guy beat me one year,
like two years ago, uh, but uh, yeah,
uh, yeah, I'm really happy with that.
Are you
planning to stay with
GitLab for the future?
Yeah.
I will definitely hang around there
as long as it, uh, I'm still amazed
that I find it's not, I don't even
feel like I'm doing the same thing.
I find new ways of like learning new
skills and learning new techniques
while staying at this target.
So, and they are very fair to me
and to other people as well, like
they're a really good program.
So it's hard to change, yes, for the like.
For whatever reason, uh, if they decide
to stop paying or rewarding or doing
another change, maybe I will move on.
Is it more after so much time, more
like just auditing the new codes
or is it still after so much time,
you still haven't explored all
functionalities that have been there?
It's still definitely a mix, even if I
think it's a bit more, uh, leaning towards
Code, but people are definitely not only
me, but other ones are definitely finding
things deep inside the old code as well.
So there's a lot of things to find there.
I imagine I haven't, haven't looked at
the source code, but I imagine there's
just so many pieces of code that are just
hard to trigger that, you know, you just.
Don't know this feature exists,
or you don't know there was this
particular case that and all of a
sudden new code does a similar thing.
And I imagine, you know, you
just randomly discover this.
Yeah.
And that's actually one thing that.
I have, uh, uh, changed or that I've
forced myself to actually finally do is
to start using their, like the GitLab
development kit, which is like the
development, uh, um, environment that they
are using when you're developing things
in GitLab and as it's, uh, Ruby based.
You actually have access to,
it's like an interpreted.
So it's like running the code as you
can have like debug breakpoints.
Yeah, exactly.
And you can also, you
can also start a console where you have
access to the code so you can trigger.
Functions and you can call functions
using things from the database, for
example, so you can say like, give
me the first project in the database
and then throw it into this function
here that takes a project or whatever.
So you
can speed up the testing a lot.
No,
yeah, definitely.
Uh, so you can, uh, when you get
a hang of it, you can start like.
Poking at things that you don't
really know how to get to yet.
Yeah, and, uh, it's really useful and
I don't have no idea why I didn't, uh,
transition to it earlier than I did.
Well, last time we were
recording the podcast, you were
just after stopping talking.
Uh, looking at the codes
through the website.
Yeah,
yeah, yeah.
Exactly.
Because I watched it and I
was like, oh, just recently I
pulled GitLab to my local disk.
Yeah.
Yeah, so there's definitely things
that I'm doing a bit more structured.
Yeah.
At the moment, yeah.
And now I think about it,
for a lot of projects.
Probably you can speed up the testing
when you have the source code,
obviously, and especially when you
have the debugging access, you can,
instead of like running the intruder
attack or something like this.
You can just do a for loop and
run a function in the for with
different inputs and stuff like this.
Yeah.
And actually something that really
inspired me as well was, uh, I don't
know if you saw this, uh, this SAML
bypass, uh, bug that was also like
really impressive, uh, in the, on its
own, like the bug was really impressive.
Yeah.
And also like really old
code, uh, and super critical.
But, uh, I saw some write up
like when some other people like
tried a similar thing, they were
like recreating it or whatever.
And they sort of like broke out a
piece of the code and built their
own little like in isolation and
they could remove the things that
they knew didn't really impact.
And then they could like iterate,
uh, looking at this piece
of code, uh, really quickly.
And that's a really inspired me.
I will try to do more of that as
well doing during court code review.
Can you, can you specify this?
I don't think I fully got the,
so they, I think in that blog post,
they wanted to see how GitHub in
that case were handling the sample.
Uh, their sample implementation, so they
took the code, uh, that you can extract
from GitHub if you, uh, figure it out
and they just took that piece of the
library and they, uh, recreated like.
Almost like building a test case.
If you're a developer, like mocking
some parts and just like making
sure that it works good enough.
And then they could run like a lot of
tests on it quickly because they don't
have to go through the whole application.
They just break out that piece of code.
Like try to break it and then try to
fit it into the application again.
Oh, because there were two blog
posts about the Samuel bypass
one was GitLab on GitHub, right?
And I think I only read the GitLab one.
Oh, yeah.
And the one you're saying is GitHub.
Yeah I think it was
from the so they discovered
this back through like Buzzing
the, the, the, the, the Samu.
Yeah.
I don't know if they've busted, but at
least they broke it out to test it very
quickly with like automation to just like
send a bunch of, because then they could
remove some of the, the things that would
make it slow, that you would have like
certain timestamp checks or whatever.
That doesn't really matter
for the final exploit.
Yeah.
That's nice.
I also wanted to, to, to, uh, understand
someone a bit after this, because
still I spend a lot of time on the
SSO, but Samuel's, Samuel's like, he's
there and there's Samuel Ryder and I
may try the attack from, from this.
And then it's pretty much
end of my knowledge about it.
If you were to approach a new system that
is GitLab, how would you start doing this?
It's been on my to do list since like
going full time to, to expand, to
have like, uh, one or two more targets
to be like my main go to targets.
Uh, I haven't really managed to do it yet.
Um, I think one of the reasons that I've
managed to stay for so long at GitLab
is to, uh, Because I, I found it like
interesting as well, like the application,
the functionality connected to my job as
a developer, like it's resonated with me.
Um, so I would approach it sort of
like I approach this, I guess, like.
Trying to find the functionality that I
want to test that I have a like a hunch
that something could break and then I
test that and then like move around in
the application is to try to find and
that's sort of like what's the luxury,
I guess, with doing bug bounties is
that no one is checking on you, like how
thorough you go through the application or
wherever you can just like, Browse around.
Yeah.
There's no, no, no consequences
from missing a bug.
No, exactly.
Uh, except like mental.
Yeah.
Uh, but, and also, I mean, you have
to, so one of the big changes for, from
going full time, uh, is that I now have
to rely on the income from bug bounties.
To actually pay my bills and my
own salary and all of that so that
that sort of Shift did happen like
from day one that you at least you
sort of have to find things, right?
Uh, and that there is like a mental
shift there that, uh, uh, if you don't
like constantly find something that is
like bringing income, it starts to be.
So even if you're like free to do
whatever you want, at least you have
to like, it has to be bring something.
Yeah.
You're not, you don't
feel completely free.
No.
And I'm, I'm, but I'm still.
in the camp of, uh, uh, my big, uh, like
inspiration when, before I went full
time, I listened a lot to like interviews
with Alex Chapman and he's like ideas
of like finding fewer, but bigger bugs.
And also like not really doing it
like to maximize Uh, income, but like
a sufficient income and like enough
and also enough to be able to keep it
interesting and, uh, and doing it for
the fun of like learning and exploiting.
Yes.
But at the same time, I actually,
it's funny because I thought about him
before you mentioned his name because
he had the exchange, um, or just a post
on, on blue sky recently about Yeah.
Escalating some bugs, some as
always, probably a Chromium RCE
and also even though he keeps it
fun, he also as a full time hunter
looks at the return on investment.
And he was saying, you know, um, on a
low paying program, perhaps you can be,
if the program, let's say downgrades
your back to a medium in case in his
case, it's an RCE where he can, uh,
access the, um, the AWS access keys.
So.
He can't really prove the impact.
He has to rely on the team
and the team says it's medium.
And the whole post was about escalating
this to a more, a bigger severity bug.
But then he was like, if this program
doesn't play that well, there's no.
I actually had the similar shrink.
I had, as I told you before, I was
spending some time on the program that has
like the typical hacker one, uh, payouts.
So the medium is 500, the high is 1000.
So I thought if I have the, let's say
the SSRF and I would like to approach.
you to escalate from medium to high.
I'm still getting the same 500.
So, and also there's some, somebody
else, um, puts in their time and
effort and maybe they are rewarded.
So in the end it's, it's plus EV, but
there's, it's not like a no brainer if
you think about it from the full time.
It's actually something that I've
been thinking about, like, Pros and
cons of different programs lately.
And one another thing that I'm
really happy about at the the
GitLab program is that they don't
have like a, a linear bounty table.
Yeah.
It's like, I don't know, it's exponential.
Exponential.
I don't think it's exponential.
Yeah.
But we
know that the, yeah.
Yeah.
That graph, if you have the curve that
if.
If you move from medium
that tops at like 2.
4k or something, and you end up
at high, which starts at like
five and ends at 15 or something.
And then the critical starts at like 20.
So there's a real incentive to
at least try to escalate to high.
Like that jump is really important.
Yeah.
And other companies like say, for example,
GitHub, where I haven't hunted as much,
but they really like, they pay like 4k
for mediums, which is, uh, impressive.
And I think you can get even more,
you can get up to like 10k for
medium, but the criticals are still
end at 30, like the same as GitLab.
So it's much more linear and helping out,
as you say, in that scenario makes less.
So I really like the, the exponential
thing because it's incentivized, like
working together and like pushing bugs
to, uh, their limits sort of, so to speak.
Yeah.
Also makes sense.
If you have a lot of, I imagine you have
loads of gadgets hidden somewhere, so
all of a sudden you can chain them and
then instead of 500 plus 500, you have.
You know, much more than one plus one.
So yeah.
Interesting.
Although when I look at the program, I
think I prefer the linear one because I
think in the, at the end of the day, you
end up reporting highs, maybe, maybe the
one you said where the high is also higher
than it makes sense because there are.
quite a lot of programs that
are sort of flat up until
the high and then exponential
critical, which they never pay.
No, exactly.
Yeah.
So I
definitely agree that you want to
have those high mediums as well.
Uh, and in a way you kind of get
spoiled with like these big programs.
And I don't know, maybe that's at
least for me, that my way of working
is that I spend a lot of time.
pretty slowly on this one program, uh,
finding like one, two, three issues,
uh, and then like nothing and then
something more and like doing that
sort of work on a program that's like
Topes out that like three K wouldn't
be, it's just not worth it for me.
So I skip all of those, uh,
invitations or whatever to, uh, I
think there's enough bugs on the,
the big, the big targets out there.
So that's why I, If I'm not looking at
GitLab, I'm usually just like looking
at, well, like Chrome or whatever
else, like big, big applications.
Yeah, we can maybe jump to this.
Last time you said you were
planning to do some browser hacking.
How has this gone?
Yeah, it hasn't really
gone as planned, I guess.
I still have it on my, I report things.
Once in a while, like smaller issues that
I find when I still tinker a lot with
Chrome and web standards and web features
and things like that, even if I'm maybe
in my main hunting, trying to move a
bit more to the back end bugs and stuff
like that as well to increase impact.
But, uh, I definitely, I find some
like quirks and strange things
once in a while, and then I report
them, but I haven't done it in the
consistent way that I would have hoped.
So,
so it's more like you're
working on something and you
have the idea of something that
could be a bug in the browser
and
then you're more reported rather
than actually spend time researching.
Yeah.
Uh, and I mean, I, I guess it's
a big, it's quite a big hurdle to
spend all that time to actually start
finding things, uh, in the browsers.
Uh, like consistently, but, uh, it's still
a dream to be able to do that as well.
Uh, it's like one of the biggest like
open source projects that you can attack.
Would you like to learn like
the memory related bugs to find
actual RCEs and stuff in browsers?
Or are you still trying to stick to To
this kind of bug that sort of requires
only the web web based knowledge.
Yeah, it hasn't really caught
my interest, uh, that much.
So maybe because I, I think
it looks really hard, but, uh,
uh, yeah, maybe eventually.
I mean, I, I've been Trying to move to the
back end and like more proper code review
on GitLab during the last year at least.
Uh, and it's been, uh, very interesting.
So I'm like moving in that direction,
but not at that like low level
as when you are finding those
kind of memory corruption things.
Yeah.
It's for me, it's, it's crazy.
Can you give us an example of the, of a
bug from the browser that you reported?
I imagine if they are in Chromium, I
guess the issue tracker is public, no?
Yeah.
Yeah, I guess, uh, I think I actually
saw, maybe you mentioned something
about it, and I was supposed to write
a blog post and then I found a bypass
to it, but now that speaks as well.
So, uh, that was, um, like a funny, uh,
I hadn't really thought much about it,
that you could like, serve HTML in xml?
Yeah.
Or like x html.
Uh, and also in sbg, like all of
these, like XML based, uh, like
languages that are baked into browsers.
And then I remember like, so this was,
uh, maybe at the time where we had our
last interview, like two years ago or
something, I think Ren Reinepack, uh,
he posted some tweet about like someone
had stolen his, uh, POC, like bragged
about it on Twitter about just like how
to build like an XML, HTML attack and
like getting execution through like.
XML, HTML, and I started to
play with that because I hadn't
really thought too much about it.
So I played around with it and tested
it and then all of a sudden, I,
because I knew that you could get
something so Uploaded on GitLab,
which I always test my things on.
And I put some HTML in an, I don't
remember if it was in an, uh, s
VG or, uh, some other XML file.
I was on my bus from work and I, I was
doing this on my phone, like hacking, uh,
. And uh, all of a sudden, like I saw my eye
frame that I have made, like on GIT Labs.
web page in this XML
document that I have created.
And I got like really hyped.
This was during like a 20
minutes transit from work.
And I was like, ran home and like,
shit, this is like, probably like
the biggest thing that I've ever
found, like some sort of like bypass.
On there, like, because it was
on the, when you can look at
like raw content of a file.
Yeah, you can do that on GitHub
and the GitLab and whatever.
You can click the raw and you just
see it in as a text plane I guess.
And I, I got home and I opened
my computer and I looked at
it and it was just text again.
Uh, so that was really disappointing.
But I looked at my phone and it was
rendering at HTML and, uh, at that
time it, it took a while for me to
figure out what's actually going on,
but I had stumbled on a bug where.
Webkit were actually like mine
sniffing, which is an old concept when
the browsers try to figure out what
sort of content you are providing.
Yeah.
So which usually happens when
there is no content type.
Exactly.
But the issue here with Webkit.
On iOS.
So like they have, uh, two different
branches for one, for uh, uh,
the desktop and one for iOS.
And, um, yeah.
So for some reason they
were mime sniffing.
Even if you served text plane, if you
had like an a dot, like an extension
of XML or SVG or whatever, or JP
G or like, yeah, you could serve
whatever sort of content you wanted.
Oh,
it worked for an extension?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh, so you could serve just x remote.
No, you could serve anything as long,
so it will, it would first look at
the extension of the name or the path.
And then it would look at the name
in the content disposition, I think.
So even if that was like xml,
and then it would look at the
content or something like that.
It was really messed up.
And I had some fun with it because,
Apparently, it worked on GitLab.
I didn't really manage to bypass CSP fully
because you're still restricted by CSP,
but on the self hosted one, you could
get access and on GitLab, I could manage
to do some like click jacking, yeah.
Uh, CSRF thing to actually do things
because you could render and also you
could render like a login screen and
yeah, I think that that was in the report.
Yeah, exactly.
You, that was form SRC and HTTPS URL.
So I think you created the login
form to your website Exactly,
which would be auto-filled.
So if the user clicks the button
or is, is somehow click jacked,
it also, actually also send it
back to get the two A code as well.
I built this whole, okay, nice.
PC so you have like two SBG
files, one for the getting the
passwords and one for the code.
And everything was like
loaded on the GitLab page.
I, I had a lot of fun with it, but
uh, in the end it didn't really.
Uh, pay that much, but, uh, it was,
so you reported it both to
get lab and to Apple as well.
Yeah, exactly.
Uh, and, uh, actually I also
reported it to Chrome because
it worked on Chrome on iOS.
Okay.
Which is sort of a bug bounty hack, uh,
that they sometimes, uh, uh, step in and
like push for changes, uh, because they
are forced to use the web kit on iOS, but,
uh, you can, uh, because Apple, they don't
really pay for those kinds of issues.
Yeah.
So you didn't get paid from Apple?
No.
Uh, but Chrome paid me some.
That's
good.
That's weird.
Yeah.
That's strange.
And then I was like a year ago or
something, I was actually gonna write to
like a blog post about this whole thing.
And then when I was like testing
my payloads, I found a bypass to
it because They had only fixed like
some of these extensions, but, and I
think that I had left, for example,
XHTML for some reason, they were
still like mime sniffing that bug.
So today is XHTML any helpful in
terms of not looking for browser
bugs, but bugs in websites?
Not really.
I guess there are like lists
out there of type of files that
will allow you to render HTML.
Yeah.
And that's one of them.
And SVG is another one.
And there are
some So it's useful if there
is a block list of extensions.
Yeah, sort of.
If they look like HTML files
or whatever and you can get HTML in there.
Yeah.
Uh, otherwise it's just, uh, uh,
harder to work with HTML because
you have to be strict to the
.
Yeah.
Uh,
XML standards.
Yeah.
I had the, the case recently, which
makes less sense than your example.
'cause I was testing a website,
um, and I could go through
the re and I, I wanted to.
Connect my Tik Tok account with
like the real account, which has
followers because I needed to pass some
thresholds for some stuff, something.
And as the testing browser, I use any
Chromium based browsers as my personal
browser, I use Safari, uh, which I know is
insecure and I shouldn't do it, but I like
it.
And I realized that I can go through
the flow, uh, like register on the
website without confirming the email
if I go through the particular flow.
So then I was trying to reproduce
this in a Chromium based browser.
It didn't work.
Of course, it took me
a while to figure out.
And for some reason, in Uh, I don't
think it's a client side thing.
It's like a server side profiling.
It allows me to go through
the registration without
confirming the email on Safari.
Not on other browsers.
I like limited all the other variables
and I guess they just have, you
know, different flows for different.
Yeah.
It was, it was fun.
I mean, that's one of the fun things
with the browser, looking for browser
quirks and bugs is that you have, at
least you have three big targets and
they behave differently sometimes.
And so you always have this like.
Uh, yeah, you can test it and it's
pretty fun trying to find these
like discrepancies between them.
And I don't know, uh, so one thing that
actually came out of this, I made a small
challenge, uh, a web challenge thing
that I sometimes post on my social media.
Uh, I'm moving a bit more to blue sky.
Uh, then, uh, Twitter at the moment,
but I made one that was, uh, it was
related to this XML XHTML thing.
Uh, I don't remember, really
remember what I was trying to do.
I think it was.
It's like filtering a lot of things
that you could then in HTML, you could
like bypass it by using like namespaces.
So you could like prepend all of the
HTML tags with like X colon and then the
release and you can like create this like
fake HTML that could bypass something.
And then a lot of people sent in
solutions where you can use this.
It's in XML, uh, which is also connecting
to SAML because SAML is also XML.
So they also have this, uh, idea of
like some sort of like transformers.
So like tags that transform
the own, the document.
Um, maybe connected to like XXE
things as well, but you can like
transform the document in place.
Like when it's rendering, some people
like managed to bypass my sanitation by
like transforming the document in place.
And there's definitely
something that you could.
There's things to learn there that
could potentially do something.
So that was, uh, yeah, so maybe
there is something to them,
uh, that you can still use.
Yeah.
I feel like a lot of the browser
challenges, even though they are
made by people like you, who know a
lot about the client side security,
still, they often have unintended
solutions because of things like this.
So it just shows you how
complex the client side is.
Yeah.
Speaking of these challenges, how often.
Or maybe, which features of these
challenges, where you have like limited
car sets or strange CSP, which of these
things you use in those challenges
are the most useful in real life bugs?
So, I have actually, this year, I
think I've used Like three or four,
like really strange browser quirks in,
uh, like escalations of, uh, client
side bugs that some things that I've,
I thought like I would never probably
be like be able to use this or like,
why, why would I ever have to use this?
But then I found myself in like a corner
where the only way to get out was like
using one of these like strange gadgets.
And that's what I find.
So a lot of time when I do my small
challenges things, it's one way to get,
like, I like the interaction between
these, like, really smart people.
They're always like, it's
sort of like a fishing thing.
They send you like really smart payloads
so you can learn a lot from these
really like super talented people.
But um, It's also often they are
like based in something that I have
encountered on the real target.
And then I just tweak it to
like fit whatever I, either
what I found interesting.
So instead of like doing a blog
post or whatever, I do a small
challenge so that people can like
get the experience of finding.
Um, something themself, which is
sometimes like more useful than
reading about what someone has done.
Uh, but then also some, I made a
challenge recently that was more
like an open ended research thing.
I don't know if you saw it, but like
you, you were supposed to like try
to get like the smallest payload.
Yeah.
So I could like fetch.
A script and execute it.
And that was more like a research
question, like I didn't really have
time to do too much on it myself.
I did enough to use it on a real target,
but then it was like this thought,
like, how small could you make this?
And it was really fun to see all
these people, uh, come together
and try to like break it down.
And then they also found like,
uh, mistakes by me in my actual
challenge, abused it to make it
even smaller and stuff like that.
It's really fun.
Yeah.
So what were the other gadgets that you
used in your life that you didn't expect?
So I guess some of them I still keep as.
Yeah, of course.
There's also like one change from
becoming like full time hunter.
You kind of have to start to build
your own toolbox of things that
you, uh, that you can become like
good at and that you can bring
Forward when you need it, I guess.
But I had one really fun one that
I got to use together with Matan.
That's a good
call up story.
We have had some good, he found
some fun things on GitLab that we
have then collaborated on, like
taking them a bit further and doing
some bypasses and things like that.
Uh, but we had one situation when we, and
that's like, and then this is really a
quirk and a niche, but we could, we were
stuck in a web worker, which is a, like
a thread in, uh, like an execution thread
of JavaScript, but we needed to get to
a service worker, which is another sort
of web worker, but the service worker
is more like in control of navigation.
And.
You can use a service worker to
like control what sort of content is
served to the application and so on.
And then you usually you
cannot really make that switch.
But for some reason, if you go to MDM
and look at the description of web
workers, you can actually see that
like there's one green box on like that
you can access the service worker, um,
functionality or API from a web worker.
And then it's just like green on
Safari, which is like super strange.
All of the other browsers have like,
uh, close this off, like for a long time
ago, like you cannot touch or create a
service worker worker from a web worker.
But, uh, for some reason,
Safari allows this.
Yeah.
So we were, and when, so yeah, we
found that and we managed to like.
make the jump.
If someone was using Safari, you
could make this jump and that could
finish our chain that would, it was
like a big chain of like random stuff.
But I was really, really happy
that we managed to use this like
forgotten, I guess, uh, feature
that I don't see any use for it.
I have no idea why it's still there.
And it's also like documented, so
it's not a bug or whatever, it's a
That's why I'm saying
I shouldn't use Safari.
Yeah.
But it is well integrated, what can I do?
I can't help myself.
How about content security policy?
What do you do when you have
the XSS or HTML injection?
And there is CSP, what's your
first What do you first look at?
Yeah, I don't remember if I, when we
spoke two years ago, if I was already,
uh, deeply invested in, uh, CSP bypasses,
I don't think
so, but it's, it's become
one of those things.
I really enjoy it just as I
enjoy cross site scripting,
which I find to be like a puzzle.
Like I, I enjoy it in the same way as
like solving Sudoku's or puzzles or
crosswords Uh, and the CSP bypasses
a lot of times can be like, it's like
an extension of cross site scripting
and something that you can, uh, prove.
I like it way more than WAF bypasses
like web application firewalls.
Those to me feel very random and
strange and you cannot really use them.
I mean, you can use logic against them,
but they don't really interest me because
they're very like, they're specific
for the application and they are like,
you, you have to throw like ugly things
at it while a CSP bypass is often more
beautiful because you're bending the
rules and you're like finding these
gadgets and things to, to get passive.
So yeah, I don't know.
I don't know.
And the only, the way to do it
is of course, just like the, the
holy grail is to get a full XSS.
So you have to first go to like script
source and see whatever they allow there.
And if it's too hard, maybe
you cannot do anything.
And then you can start looking at,
so like what sort of like loose,
you know, like, Um, uh, HTML things.
Can you do, can you do like form
injections and, uh, form actions
or base tag, uh, take over the
base tag and stuff like that.
So we covered, you can do the form
to your website if it's possible.
Yeah, exactly.
You need the, the, the
forum SRC or form action.
Is that what controls this?
Yeah.
Form action.
Um, and it's, so the, the, the
thing with that one is that it's
not covered by default source.
Yeah.
That's important.
And the same with the base.
Yeah.
So base and form are like outside of that
default, because the default is usually
set to something like none or self.
So if you cannot execute JS, these are
the sort of two things that you look at.
Yeah.
Uh, but then also for the JavaScript, like
if they have a white list, you of course
go and look for like script gadget things.
And, uh, speaking of like gadgets that
I've been able to use, like just this
past year, I've been able to use the,
this trick where you, you have a white
listed domain with a path, but then if
you hit like a redirect on that path.
Then you're allowed to hit, uh, or like
load code that is like from the base.
Oh,
okay.
So after the redirect, any path
will be ignored and they will
only look at the base URL of
each of your whitelisted objects.
So wait again.
So you have some, some path.
In the CSP and the resource should
start with this path, but then if under
this part, there's a redirect, you are
allowed to do anything on the same host.
Yeah, exactly.
Okay,
that's interesting that there is a
validation but only to the host, no?
Yeah, and I think one thing that a
lot of might miss there is that you
can also like, After the redirect,
the path requirement is removed
from like everything on the CSP.
I guess you can actually start to look
again on like these other ones as well.
Okay.
Like whatever, what, so
for example, the frame.
Source, like whatever you can frame,
uh, you might find something there
that they are allowing you to frame
like slash, uh, assets slash whatever.
But if you can redirect that, you can all
of a sudden frame things from the base.
Uh, so that I've been able to use in
like these sort of like click jacking
scenarios where they maybe allow you to
frame something, but then you can frame
something that is, uh, much more dangerous
because it's like on the default.
Yeah.
And I believe still the Chrome
passport manager autofills.
the password inside the iframe,
even if it's different origin?
I don't think it's, if it's different
origin, I don't think it does it anymore.
Okay.
I think it does it if it's sandboxed then.
Maybe.
Because I think we had this case.
Um, okay.
Yeah.
There's something with this.
It's a flip.
I've seen things like that as well,
but uh, I think that's really It's
important to keep in mind that there
are more parts to the CSP as well.
Yeah.
So it's like the script is one thing, but
you can do other fun things like framing
and things that could be dangerous.
How to, let's say you have some custom
JavaScript that's whitelisted as a
script SRC, and it has, I don't know,
thousands of lines after beautifying.
How would you start even looking for
a, for a gadget to exploit to, to,
to To be able to escalate your, your
access to, to execute JS through this.
Yeah,
I don't know.
I haven't really been in that
situation too many times, I guess.
Like a lot of the, for some reason,
the big companies actually have
their like source maps out there.
So you can see it, uh, where I've
been hunting GitHub and you can
actually see what's going on.
But otherwise, I mean, that's one of
the things that you get Uh, not for
free, but what that, uh, like a bonus.
For spending a lot of time on, um, one
target or like a couple of targets is that
you, you find these things and then you
can keep them in your notes, for example,
because I think you use the same
GitLab CSP bypass a few times at least.
No, because I think there was the
same bypass that kind of everyone knew
about and people used it for years.
Yeah.
Uh, there's been a few of
them, uh, they've been starting
to close off More and more
it's not good for you, is it
,
but there's still, there's still ways to,
to get around it and depending on what
you can, uh, what you can inject or not.
So, and I mean, it also adds,
even if it's boring, that when
they remove them, it also adds to
the game that you have to find.
Yeah.
And when you find a new one, you're,
you get really happy about that as well.
What other client side bugs are
you, are you finding apart from XSS?
Something that I've been, uh, also have
had quite like a surprising amount of,
uh, success with is, uh, DOM clobbering.
Okay.
As, uh, I'm not.
On its own, but like as a part of a
chain or a gadget or whatever, um, it's
actually way more useful than you like
initially think just to be able to,
for example, on, I had one bug on, uh,
Gmail, it was sort of a combination.
The worst kind of in bug bounties
when you mix programs, which ends up
that no one really wants to award you.
So it was a combination of like, you can
in emails, of course, you can send HTML.
That's why it looks so beautiful
and you can send forms.
If you want to, and some email
clients will actually render
these forms in different ways.
And they will do some
sanitation and stuff like that.
But Gmail, for example, will actually
render the complete form with form.
It will change the passwords
fields to text fields.
So they will be of type text, but it
will have the whole form and everything.
Uh, and if you click submit, it will
pop up a warning saying like, you're
submitting things to an external page.
Do you really want to do this?
And you click no.
Uh, so I, I found a bug, uh, using.
There was a couple of, uh, password
managers that could do like auto
filling and they don't really care about
whether it's a password field or not.
They're really like.
Uh, happy to fill whatever, like
if you give it a name, a password
and not the type password, a lot of
them will fill it anyway in plain
text, which is really strange.
Uh, but they will do it.
And I also found a way to trick
some of these password managers
to actually auto submit it.
If you put the text field inside
of the submit button, because they
will actually to, because they want
to pretend that they are human.
So they will actually send like
a click action to the form field.
And if that is inside of the submit
button, the button will, the event
will propagate up to the button
and it will click it and submit it.
So you have like.
Login field, a normal password
field, and another password
field inside of the button.
Yeah, or the password field that
they want, because they will fill
it first, and then they will trigger
the Oh yeah, yeah, okay, so you're
saying the key to react, correct.
Uh, and I tried to submit that, but the,
the, the, the password, uh, uh, storage
companies are like, I don't know their
threat models, it's really strange,
they don't care about things like that.
Yeah, I'm not having a good time with
But so I, so that was like one sort of
a bug that I, I felt like it was a bit
strange that this one password manager
did actually allow you to autofill.
When you open an email, you had a
form in Gmail and it would autofill
your Gmail credentials because as
you said, they will look at just
like Google, uh, or whatever, like,
yeah,
Yeah.
And, uh, and top,
top window.
Exactly.
And so some
people might have like the password saved
then on the Gmail, so it'll fill there and
it'll click, but then you will get blocked
by this, uh, uh, Google protection thing.
Yeah.
And then I went into the source
code and, and found that this check
they were doing was like, they found
the form element or like, they,
they catched the, the submission.
Uh, and then they looked at
the element and they did like.
Element dot target, uh, equals
blank, like question mark.
And one thing that they did was if you
put the form in there, they would put
like target blank because they wanted this
thing to trigger Google when they rendered
the form, they wanted it to trigger.
Uh, but then I could use Dom
clobbering them to put, uh, to
name one of these fields to target.
So you have a form and inside
of the form you have an input
field with the name target.
That's it.
And then if you have the element of the
form and you do dot target, you will
get the input field and you will not get
the value of the target thing and the
input field will not equal equal blank.
So then you would skip the, so the
final, uh, POC was actually like, if
you opened an email, your password
thing would autofill and submit it
and you would lose your credentials.
Yeah.
That's a cool bug.
For which nobody has paid.
No, no, no.
Google actually paid me for it.
They paid me for the dom club ring.
So that was like one three,
three, seven or whatever it is.
They're like, yeah, that's cool.
So that was really good.
And I think that to be fair, I
think I got like 500 or something
for the From the password manager.
Okay.
So they did something.
I don't really know what they
fixed, but they did something.
But I thought it was, I mean,
the book, the bug, it looks
much cooler than the payout.
Yeah.
And it's a cool idea as well.
I don't think I ever used dumb
clobbering on the reward targets.
I feel like I see your bugs.
I see Martin bugs.
I see all the client and I'm like,
Oh, I should spend more time on
the client.
Um, how about post message related bugs?
Do you?
Do you find a lot of stuff that,
that starts with a post message?
I, I haven't actually
looked too much into it.
Uh, I know that it's one of those fields
that are still like ripe with bugs.
Uh, so like one of those like
untouched areas where there are, it
seems at least to be bugs everywhere.
But, uh, I haven't really spent
too much time on it, actually.
Probably I should, but I
feel the same
way.
Um, maybe client side prototype
pollution is the next one that
I don't spend too much time on.
Uh, yeah, yeah.
So, so when you, when you asked
me, like, what sort of client side
bugs I found, find these days, uh,
that was one that I thought about,
but I have actually never found it.
And it feels very strange and
niche to me that it should exist.
I know that people sometimes
find them, um, but it's, yeah,
it's, to me, it doesn't feel like
something that is like super common.
So it's definitely more common to find as
something else that you mentioned, these
like client side path, traversal things.
Yeah.
Which was actually something
that I, I think I, I think you
made a video of one of those.
Yeah, my, my video was about your client
side path traversal in GitLab because I
didn't see a real world example of this.
And then we had the interview
and they told me you had, so
then I covered it in the video.
And I don't think there is
many public write ups about
client side post reversals.
No, I mean, there's been a
lot of discussions with it.
And I think there's also been
a lot of tooling made recently.
I haven't really used anything,
but I think that people have
both, uh, Like Kaido plugins and
extensions to Chrome and stuff like that.
Yeah, I think the critical thinking guys
created the browser extension for it.
For me, it's more, it's
more of a hierarchy.
Like I think that the reason why I
haven't felt like I need to use it,
it's the way I'm looking for these
kinds of bugs is usually on GitLab.
Maybe I find a way, like a new way
of getting content into the app.
So that's like where I start like,
okay, if I connect this piece here,
it will render data over here.
And then, so then I start from the
top, like, okay, I want it to set.
And then like, okay, it doesn't work.
Okay, then I want dumb
clobbering or whatever.
I want to HML injection
and then that doesn't work.
And then I try like, Oh, maybe I can do a
client side path commercial or whatever.
Yeah.
And so it's more of a, I just go
through different bugs depending on the
injection I have, like going from, I
found like a source and I tried to like.
Do something with it.
So I've, I've actually found a
few CSP, uh, client side path
protocols, uh, this year as well.
Uh, they're a bit hard sometimes to,
if they only make, I found some that
just made like a get, uh, request and
that makes it quite hard to exploit.
Uh, I managed to show some impact
by again, like chaining it with, uh,
as you hear, like there's a lot of
chaining of small things, but I managed
to chain it with a redirect and yeah,
so, and so the, the get request.
It was a GET request made by Fetch, so
it contained a CSRF token in a header.
Yeah.
And then if you redirect that
request, you would actually leak
the CSRF token to your page.
Yeah.
And then you could redirect that again.
Using the CSRF, so it kind of turns
into a CSRF, uh, all the way to
run, or you can just wait for it
to like land on your domain and,
Oh yeah, cause from your website
you can directly issue a redirect,
which is already the CSRF request.
Yeah, exactly.
So
there's never like top level
navigation to your website.
No, or you could actually like leak it
and then make sure that the user ends up
on your Domain somehow and you can see
it's a bit convoluted and it doesn't,
uh, work all the time, but it was like
the best I could using a get request.
Yeah, the best, but in, um,
many targets that would use not
cookies, but some custom header
for authorization, the header would
just be leaked to your website.
Then you don't have to do anything.
Have you had much success outside GitLab
with the client side bus traversals?
No, not really.
Uh, I think it's a, it's a
bug to me at least how I work.
It would be a bug that requires me
to like know the application deeply
to know where to put it, to see where
like IDs are rendered or whatever.
Uh, so I, I haven't really, the other work
I've done has not been related to that.
Yeah.
I have found a few, but
never a gadget to exploit.
Once I had, uh, Uh, I had the
clients I passed traversal and
it was an open source stuff.
So I was looking through all the,
all the get routes because it was
a get based, all the get routes
that would make sense to chain it.
And I found one that was actually
making changes and I was happy
because I found the guidance for
client side cross reversal and then
I realized that I don't need the
client side cross reversal because
top level navigation is good enough.
So I, I got, uh, I reported this as
a CSRF and never used the client side
cross reversal, so that's my experience.
Um, Another bug that I also saw for
the first time publicly exploited in
your bug is a cross window forgery.
Can
you
tell us what cross window forgery is?
So this is actually, it's a
research from a guy that I
don't really remember his name.
It was sort of at the same time when I was
going to try to do full time bug bounties.
It's my first three months, I guess.
Uh, there was this blog post
about something that he had
named then cross window forgery.
I have his name, but I, I'm
worried I will misspell it
badly, but now I think I have to.
Yeah.
Paulus.
I mean,
he found this strange quirk in
browsers where you essentially
on if you are on the page.
And you, for example, start
pressing enter and that triggers
a new window to open your click.
If you keep pressing enter, the
click will transfer to the new
window and click on maybe something.
Yeah.
And then you can chain that with,
uh, uh, you can use the, the
hash or the fragment in the URL.
To actually like point to something
dangerous, like a button that will
accept something or do something.
And the click will like transfer to this
new window and click on that button.
Yeah,
because when you press the
space or the enter, it will
click the button that's focused.
And one way I usually use this is
probably when I do the tab on the
input field and then I do the tab for
the button and then I press the space.
So you can also do it.
If there's a hash with the ID
of the button, then it's sort
of automatically focused, right?
Yeah, exactly, exactly.
Uh, and I mean, the, the,
the, the, the write up is.
It's fun and fine and great in a lot
of ways, but it's also like a, a pretty
strange bug to like, it's, it's hard
to see if it's like, if it's good or
bad, like if it requires like really
strange behavior in a way like pressing
enter, but I had some fun with it.
Uh, this year, because I, I took it as
like an, an exercise to, to build, uh,
POCs or like to convince companies,
like, because the worst scenario that I
could think of was this, like you shame
this with this sort of like, Oh, uh,
requirement, uh, what
do you call those pages?
The consent consent screens, uh,
because the consent screen will ask
you, like, are you allowing this?
application to see
everything and access you.
And you have one button
that says like, yeah, okay.
And if you click it, it's done.
And then you have like
an account to take over.
So if that button has an ID, uh, then you
could focus that button and you can abuse
this to take over accounts essentially.
Yeah.
So my idea was that the impact
here is big, even if the, the,
like how you get there is kind
of like goofy and not really.
I don't know if it's realistic or not,
but I've sort of spent the time to
build this case that we have, or like
companies as a community has moved to
make people just like the cookie bar
has made people click on all the pages.
Yeah.
Um, you have, we have these like
recapture or capture things that When
you go to a page that you sort of
trust, like maybe you don't even trust
it, but you do something and they
say like, yeah, here's a Capcha game.
Uh, a lot of people will just do
whatever it says, like, yeah, five
clicks, type something and drag
and drop and like do whatever.
Yeah.
So I, I built a case that like, it's
not that hard to convince someone like.
Yeah, press enter three times and
then you have like a progress bar that
is like filling up and if you drop
enter, it will like go down again.
So you have to press it for
like three seconds to prove
you're a human or whatever.
Uh, so I did that POC and then I did like
a, a built like a floppy bird game or I
cloned the game from, uh, from GitHub.
And I, I just, I edit the code.
So like when you play it with the
enter and then like during a period
where you're supposed to like go
a lot of like up with the bird.
Find the space.
You have to, yeah, you have to like
enter for like you have to keep it in.
Yeah.
To get the bird up.
And during that time, I opened
this window as like a small popup
and it'll do the, the thing.
Yeah.
Uh, and to you using those two POCs.
Uh, it actually became quite easy to
convince at least these big companies
that are like hosting these sort of like
consent wealth things, uh, that this is
actually an issue because it's really,
again, it's also really easy to fix.
So the impact is high.
The fix is easy.
You just remove the ID
and, uh, you're done.
You cannot exploit it anymore.
Uh, and, uh, but still like, it's
not really maybe realistic, but.
It's, it's dangerous enough that you
could, uh, it could be worth fixing.
Yeah.
And also, it was also one of the reasons
I wanted to talk about this because I
even said it in one of the recent videos
that sometimes it's hard to get through
the triage with non standard things.
Yeah.
And because this, and I would like
this to be more standardized, so
maybe it's like widely accepted.
That, you know, okay, this is
not the, the interaction is
kind complex, but it's likely.
So, you know, it's, it's,
maybe it's not, uh, critical.
Maybe not a high, but it's, it's, in
my opinion, it's definitely a bug.
Yeah.
I, and I mean, uh, I, I must admit that
these are maybe the bugs where I found
I felt most, uh, like scammy in a way.
Like doing, uh, like
I, it's not like I was.
Super proud of what I created . Okay.
When, well, you created the
flowy, but it's cool episode.
Yeah, I, I thought it was fun to send
a game and stuff like that because I've
been really inspired by, there's been one
guy that I've seen some bugs on Chrome.
Yeah.
A lot of like.
things when, uh, you kind of like click
on these different consent things in
Chrome that they pop like, are you
allowed to use the microphone or whatever?
And there's one guy who has sent like
tens or 20 reports, like abusing this.
And it's all, he always has like a Dino
game, like a dinosaur that runs and jumps
and you have to do like different things.
And I, I thought it was
really fun to have like.
This aspect of like building a
small game as the POC, like a bit
goofy and a bit like light touch.
Yeah, it's
nice.
It was fun in that way.
And I
mean, it's worked out.
So it's, uh, it's good.
Yeah.
And it's also, I think the, as
I said, I like it because it's
something I didn't know about and I
think it's applicable fairly widely.
Yeah.
Let's now talk a little bit
about the server side bugs.
When browsing through your recent bugs on
GitLab, at least from the issue tracker,
there was a lot of denial of service bugs.
Yeah.
Especially the regular
expression based ones.
Can you talk to us more about this?
Yeah.
I was turning into the The denial of
service guy, uh, in the beginning of this
year, I, I think I counted them as well.
I think I had the 20 accepted reports
on GitLab that are like denial of
service, uh, the two different kinds.
And I've also seen that there's
been a lot of other people
reporting that I was at the moment.
Uh, yeah.
Kind of one of those.
things that happens with one of those
old programs that you see bug types like
come and go and they fix and then they
like fix the root cause uh eventually
and then people move on to something new
and at the moment like there's still a
lot of like different sending bad Content
to a GitLab server and trying to crash.
Yeah.
Uh, I, I was moving it.
I had been on a break during like December
and January and I was moving into my like
three month trying out full time in March.
So in February, I felt like I had
to like start finding something
or like get something going prior
to getting into it for full time.
And then I decided, I don't
remember how, but I had this hunch
that, okay, like we DOS bugs.
People have found them.
I have found some of them.
Regular expression denial of service.
And I decided to like, trying to actually
like, root out all of the last ones.
In GitLab.
Like why does people find
them like, once in a while.
And always like in old code.
Like why doesn't, haven't anyone just,
Found all of them, like, what's my idea?
So I started to grab through the code
base, uh, using regular expressions,
trying to find regular expressions.
Yeah.
So it was actually one of my maybe most,
uh, structural, structural attacks ever.
Like I, I got this like list of like
200, uh, potential, I think I grept for
a couple of patterns, like anything that
contained more than one star or plus.
So that's the indicator
that's sort of like
the main goal of a regular expression,
denial of service is to get the regular
expression to go into a really, really
deep nested search for something.
You have something called like
backtracking, so it tries to go as far
forward as it can, and then it goes back,
and then it goes forward again, and back
and forward, and it creates this like
exponential, uh, amount of, paths through
this, uh, whatever you're trying to hit.
And when this happens are usually
when you have like multiple asterisks
or plus it can happen in other
scenarios as well, but that's like the
sort of simple example is.
If you have wildcards one or more
times and wildcard one or more times,
and I have this string three A's,
it can be the first group can be two
A's and the second can be one, and
then it can be one, two or two, one.
And then with this simple example,
it's two different sort of, uh, I don't
know, it's the tree that's being thrown
somewhere, but, but it's two combinations.
And I assume your inputs are not, are
not three characters long, more like 3,
000.
And actually something that I had to
learn, because the theory is quite
easy, but then you actually had to
learn to break, uh, using your payload.
So after all the A's you have to
put like a B or whatever, because
it has to fail and then go back and
try again, like different paths.
Yeah.
Uh, and that can be a bit more like,
that's a super simple example, but in
different cases, it could be like, uh,
quite like convoluted, but there are like,
so you want the sandwich to be like.
almost your whole input.
Yeah.
But not sort of the last character.
At
least like there are some different
ones and that's, I actually
learned like there are some, it's
a classic like research topic.
Like there are university
people like doing like heavy
research into read, read us bugs.
Uh, and I actually tried some
like Java based Chinese research
things that I put out on this.
GitHub.
It didn't really catch more than my, like,
maybe it could do, but in the end, what
you have to do is like, you have to first
find the bad regex and then you have to
figure out if you can actually get there.
You have to figure out if it's bad
and that you can do with like a free,
there are web pages where you can
just paste regex and it will tell
you if it's, uh, like if you could,
if it could be a problem or not.
Okay.
But then you also have
to find a way to get.
The payload to that place
in the application, right?
And most of the times, as you kind
of mentioned, is that most of the
bad RegExps are not that bad, but
they are bad if you give it like
500, 000 Ks or whatever, like, Yeah.
You give it like a lot of data, then
it will break because the computers are
like, if it would be a computer like 20
years ago, it will probably break easier.
But nowadays, like they are
really, they can do a lot of work.
So, but there's a lot of those
places in, for example, GitLab
where you can get like huge data.
Into like that you control into one of
these like semi bad, uh, regis things.
Yeah.
How do they usually, what
severity do they assign?
You have two levels.
Uh, I, I can also like stay, say now
that I think Redos is in scope again.
But they have actually fixed it at
like a language level now at GitLab.
So it's sort of a dead bug.
But that's also why you see
people transitioning into this
other sort of like DOS bugs.
But they, I mean, it's a medium if you
have to be, if you have to have a user.
But what you really want to do is
you want to have, be able to send
like an unauthenticated request.
And then you get like the full, they
have some metric that you have to, you
have to, uh, trigger like a 10 second
delay on like a specific like setup with
a set of course and stuff like that.
Oh, that's, that's cool.
Yeah.
So they have it in the policy, like
how bad you have to make it for it to
become high instead of low or whatever.
So, and I actually like, I found, I guess
I found like 18 of these bugs or whatever.
And every bug I found, I found it
like one at a time and exploit them.
And I thought like, okay,
yeah, that was the last one.
Like, uh, it cannot be better than this.
And then in the end, uh, like, I
think it was like the last two I
found because I, then I had like an
epiphany, like I was taking a shower or
whatever, like a classic shower moment.
And I had, I thought like, I saw
something strange in the code.
Like, I remember that I saw
something really strange and
I went back and found it.
And it was actually in the
main, uh, speaking of old bugs,
like in the main search bar.
Yeah.
When you search for code in GitLab, you
can actually put like stars, asterisks in
your search search for wildcard matches.
And for some reason, I haven't
really thought about like how this is
implemented, but if you look at the code.
At that time, at least it, it would parse
out because it's not regex, but it's just
like a star and it acts like dot star.
And if you looked at the code, they will
actually like match and replace in your
string, all the stars with dot star.
Oh, and then create the regex from it.
And create a regex from it.
And so then I could actually create this.
Uh, the, the school book example of
like searching for, and you would, so
you could do it unauthenticated and
something that almost always exist
in all repos is the read me file.
So I could do like a, a big R
star, star, star, star, star,
star, star, star, and end it with
something that is not MD, right?
So like markdowns, it has
to end with something else.
Yeah.
Okay.
Thank you.
Uh, and then you could like break it
with, uh, it's like, and usually these
read those things, you send like a bunch
of requests to like kill all the course.
So they like end up at a hundred
percent usage, but it was really fun.
That's how I found like two
different of those in the end.
Uh, and they got rewarded as high.
So even when I thought like I had
found like the last remaining one,
I found these two and that was the
right before they put it out of scope.
So it was great.
Yeah.
You were the reason.
I
mean, they were actually really,
really nice with this because
they had in the pipeline to
actually upgrade and kill Ridos.
Uh, for good using like, uh,
updating the, the Ruby to 3.
2 or whatever it is.
But as they hadn't, the roadmap was like
in six months or something like that.
So they said like, yeah, if you
have reported it before now, it
will still be dangerous in like
six months, a six month period.
So we will still reward it and then,
okay.
Uh, we'll be heading to the
end of the, of the interview.
I think it's actually
getting quite dark here.
It is getting quite dark and we don't
have lights here, but
if
you cannot see us, we're still here.
Listen to us.
We're, we're still continuing.
Um, after just one, one more
question after so much time and
so much things learn, how do
you still learn new stuff today?
Yeah.
I, I definitely, I have not.
I will still, I think I only will still
do this as long as I am learning things.
I think that's one of the, I
can't really see myself just
doing it, the grind or whatever.
Like, uh, even if I find it really
interesting to be able to live off of it.
finding bugs and like being in
control of my time and everything.
I, one of the reasons why I also, when I,
I quit my job was that I felt like I could
learn more and quicker if I would do this
on my own, like if I can control my time.
But that also includes that I I want
to and need to learn things and how
I do it is, uh, to remind myself to
like go to the correct sources, like
reading documentation, uh, trying
to become better at using like the
right tools and like learn tools.
Uh, so with all of this, like
debugging and setting up environments
and like taking a small step.
Yeah.
Uh, each day and then we'd like
the bug types and stuff like that.
It's more of a, if you put yourself
out there and like you try, you, you
cannot just try to find whatever you
have found before you have to like act.
be, I don't know, you cannot really call
it brave, but you have to put yourself in
a position where you think you will fail.
Yeah.
And then sometimes you will
actually succeed and you
will make a new step forward.
And so, for example, I found my first
RC this year as well, which I really
didn't think I could check more
boxes after becoming a number one
at GitLab this year, but yeah, And
that's just the step when you finally
do it, it also feels quite easy.
And now maybe I only found one so far.
I have still a lot to learn.
Yeah.
Well, I think we, we all do.
Um, what are your plans for 2025
in a way, funny that I think that my
answer is really similar to when we lost.
Spoke becoming more structured, uh,
structured, uh, creating some automation.
I've actually started taking notes.
It's always been my thing.
I don't take notes, but I actually,
I've been using obsidian now and I
really, really enjoy it and, uh, I'm,
I need to get better at it, but at
least I throw things in there and I've
found myself searching for my own.
No, it's a lot.
Yeah.
Uh, so it, it definitely helps.
Uh, but yeah, and I'm browser
hacking on the list as well.
Uh, yeah.
I mean, the to do list is always like
move to a new program, uh, expand, but I
don't really have any super big, uh, I'm
looking forward to, I've had quite a good
success This year it's been intense and
there's been a lot, a lot of happening.
So I, I want, my big goal
is to survive a year.
survive, not, but like mentally.
Yeah.
Feel like it's still interesting and fun.
I don't burn out and, uh.
Maybe like settle in this new situation
of, of being in control of my own time.
Cool.
Good luck with this.
Uh, thank you so much
for, for the interview.
If you enjoyed it, uh, also you can
check out our interview from before two
years, which we mentioned a few times
there, we spoke a little bit more about
the university, about the thesis, about
getting into the, The security so if you
enjoyed this one, you will definitely
like that one as well for now Thank
you so much for listening and goodbye